JOSHUA ROCHOTTE, MI, A-CSPO

Phone: (732) 406-1929 • joshjrochotte@gmail.com • South Plainfield, New Jersey 07080 LinkedIn.com/in/joshrochotte

PERSONAL STATEMENT

A dedicated and passionate product manager serving the life sciences industry for the past 4 years. Experience in leading teams to deliver highly functional, data science focused SAAS products and wearing many hats. Looking to secure a role in product focused data analysis or product management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MEDIDATA SOLUTIONS

Product Manager, Digital Oversight

Mar 2021 to Present

- Developed detailed roadmaps for virtual monitoring and data science applications
- Lead cross platform integration effort to unite applications and user workflow
- Promoted into role within 12 months due to strong performance and organizational impact

Product Owner, RBQM

Apr 2020 to Mar 2021

- Lead 30 engineers across 3 global teams in the development of microservice analytics, metrics configuration and data review solutions, releasing new products every 3 months
- Efforts included product strategy, SCRUM practice, customer interviews, MVP development, writing detailed product requirements and mentorship of other Product Owners as a BA/PO mentor
- Passionate Encore Award received Jan 2021 for exemplified focus on company ideals

Implementation Consultant

Jul 2017 to Apr 2020

- Provided study design, consultation, training and data focused error resolution driving customer success across indications and segments on risk based quality monitoring and electronic data capture
- Networked with R&D teams as an end user and direct voice of the customer to drive new functionality
- Built 20+ clients more than 40 studies, yielding 20+ Million in revenue, consistently hitting quarterly targets

EDUCATION

Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey

2016-2018

Master of Information, Data Science | Technology, Information and Management

- Research Project: Socially Influenced Cooperation in Competitive Scenarios Online
- Beta Phi Mu, International LIS Honor Society

Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey

2013-2017

Bachelor of Arts, Psychology | Bachelor of Arts Information Technology and Informatics

- Specialization in Game Design and Innovation
- Deans List

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE

- Certifications: Google Data Analytics (2021), Product Manager Certificate (2021), A-CSPO (2021), Mini MBA Biopharma Innovation (2017), Medidata Rave Study Builder/Admin (2017)
- Programming: Python, R, SQL, Java, C#, HTML/CSS/JS
- Applications: Microsoft Office 365, Axure, IndigoDesign, Balsamiq, JustInMind, Tableau, JIRA, Confluence, Lucidchart, AHA, Draw.IO, AWS, Slack, Salesforce, Trello
- Skills: Advanced Data Analytics, Business Intelligence, Agile Development, UI/UX Design, Project Management, Workflow Design, Research and Information Management, Product Roadmaps, Relationship Management, Database Management